The Most Seductive Evil of All Time Has Now Been Unleashed in Ours.
Dracula 2000 is a thriller, horror, action film directed by Patrick Lussier.
When a team of techno-savvy thieves break into a high-security
vault, they don't discover priceless works of art...
they find a crypt unopened for 100 years.
Dracula, played by Gerard Butler.
Matthew Van Helsing, played by Christopher Plummer.
Simon Sheppard, played by Jonny Lee Miller.
Mary Heller, played by Justine Waddell.
Lucy Westerman, played by Vitamin C.
Solina, played by Jennifer Esposito.
Dracula 2000 (also known as Wes Craven Presents: Dracula 2000 and internationally as Dracula 2001) is a 2000
American horror film co-written and directed by Patrick Lussier and produced by Joel Soisson.
Starring Gerard Butler in the title role along with Christopher Plummer, Jonny Lee Miller, Justine Waddell, Omar Epps, Colleen Fitzpatrick, Jeri Ryan and Jennifer Esposito, the plot follows Count Dracula, who, after
having escaped captivity by Abraham Van Helsing following the events of the novel Dracula, arrives in New Orleans, Louisiana in the 21st century and seeks out Mary Heller, the daughter of Van Helsing.
Dracula 2000, under its promotional title Wes Craven Presents: Dracula 2000, builds upon Bram
Stoker's original 1897 novel, with Count Dracula resurrected in contemporary America.
The film was a critical and commercial failure.
Dracula 2000 was followed by two direct-to-video
sequels, Ascension in 2003 and Legacy in 2005.
Series director Lussier and Joel Soisson, who co-wrote all three films, created a plot for a
fourth film and discussed releasing it theatrically, but the film was not produced.
The film explores themes of martial arts, london,
england, fight, vampire, christianity.
The tone is dark and intense.